

BASHIR DAUDA

• DETAILS •

297, Pipeline, Kubwa, FCT Abuja Abuja, 901101 Nigeria +2348145644352 bashir4windowslive@gmail.com

> Nationality Nigerian

> · LINKS ·

Github

linkdedin

SKILLS

JavaScript

React

Node.js

Redux

HTML & CSS

Tailwindcss

Express.js

MongoDB

Git

GitHub

Leadership

Ability to Work in a Team

Communication Skills

HOBBIES

Exploring distant land, Getting lost in a good book, Every kind of sport

LANGUAGES

English

Yoruba

Hausa

PROFILE

Dedicated and highly skilled software engineer with exceptional communication, time management, and computer skills, I am excited to apply my expertise to a challenging role at your company. With a passion for software development and a proven track record of success, I am confident in my ability to help your organization achieve its goals.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Software Engineer Intern at HIIT PLC, Abuja

May 2019 — January 2020

- For a period of six months, I completed an internship at HIIT PLC where I acquired valuable skills that have laid the foundation for my career as a software engineer. During the internship, I gained experience in web development and computing, including proficiency in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, PHP, SQL, and computer networking. These skills have been instrumental in my success as a software engineer today.
- Skills: SQL · HTML5 · JavaScript · Bootstrap · Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)

Software Engineer at Scholapay, Lagos

February 2021 — December 2021

- During my role, I collaborated with external teams to develop specifications
 and achieve high-quality deliveries, designed and implemented solutions using
 JavaScript and web development tools such as HTML/CSS, facilitated a seamless
 transition from Figma designs to pixel-perfect apps, and established a code review
 workflow to encourage the creation of reusable and efficient code, with the aim of
 identifying and addressing issues before they reached production.
- Skills: Software Development · Redux · React.js · Tailwind CSS

Software Engineer at Center for disease control, Abuja

March 2022 — August 2022

As a Full Stack Engineer with experience in the MERN stack, I have worked with external teams to create specifications and achieve quality deliverables. I have designed and developed solutions using JavaScript and web development tools such as HTML/CSS, ensuring smooth transitions from Figma designs to final applications. Furthermore, I have set up a review process to promote the creation of reusable and optimized code, aiming to detect and address

EDUCATION

B.Sc Computer Science, Bayero University Kano, Kano

March 2016 — September 2020

¶ REFERENCES

Mr Abubakar Abdulwahab from IBM

abudawud92@gmail.com · +2347066565263

Haruna Yakubu from Supervisor (Bayero University, Kano)

+2347036188150